natashaskitchen.com 2019-12-27

# Privacy Policy - NatashasKitchen.com

Natasha’s Kitchen is dedicated to maintaining your privacy privacy and the protection of your personal information. This privacy policy details what information we collect on NatashasKitchen.com (Website) and how that information is used. It also includes your opt-out options. By using this Website, you are consenting to the practices and collection of information detailed in this privacy policy.

## WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?

The information we collect falls into two categories: (1) information you supply when you subscribe to receive emails, enter giveaways or leave comments on the website, and (2) tracking information collected as you navigate through our site.

When registering on our site, you may be asked to enter your: name, e-mail address or website. You may, however, visit our site anonymously.

## WHAT DO WE USE YOUR INFORMATION FOR?

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

1\. To personalize your experience  
(your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs)

2\. To improve our website  
(we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you)

3\. To improve our customer service  
(your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs)

4\. To administer a promotion, contest, survey or other site feature

## SIGNING UP TO RECEIVE EMAIL NEWSLETTERS:

When you fill out one of the emails subscription opt-in boxes, we will send you the email series you signed up for which consists of 3 to 5 emails. Following that, emails are sent 2 to 3 times per week with new recipes and posts, roundups and news from NatashasKitchen.com. If you subscribe to our email newsletters through our subscription box, you are consent to store and process your data in order to receive our newsletters. The email you provide is used only for email subscription communication purposes and never shared or distributed to third parties. Your email is stored with our subscription service provider who has certain levels of security to protect your personal data.

To change your subscription preferences, click the “preferences” button that is included with the email you receive from us then follow the steps in the email that you receive once you click the “preferences” button. We track how readers engage, interact and click through our newsletters.If you wish to disable view and click tracking, you may do so by clicking the “preferences” button as well.

If you no longer wish to receive newsletters, please click the “unsubscribe” button at the bottom of the newsletters you receive in your inbox or email: natasha AT natashaskitchen DOT com and let me know that you would like to be removed. You may also request to have your data entirely erased from our subscription service.

## PUSH NOTIFICATIONS:

When you opt in to receive push notifications, Push Crew is used to send you notifications through your web browser Information for Push Crew’s privacy policies and practices are located here: [Push Crew](https://pushcrew.com/privacy-policy/). If you signed up for push notifications and no longer wish to receive them, find detailed instructions here.

## WHAT INFORMATION IS TRACKED?

**Cookies:** We may use “cookies” from time to time which is a feature of major browser applications that allows us to store information such as your personal preferences when you visit our site. This may include only showing each visitor a popup once during our visit to the Website. We do not collect any personally identifiable information in cookies. We do not employ any mechanisms on our site to capture data other than cookies.You can turn off cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings or by managing these preferences in programs such as Norton Internet security or similar security programs, however doing so can affect how you are able to interact with our Website as well as other sites.

**Your Browser Information:** As with most sites, NatashasKitchen.com, may gather and store ifnormation such as IP addresses, MAC addresses, type of browser, ISP, how you arrived at our Website via referring and exit pages, your operating system, date and time of your visits and click stream data or how you navigate our Website. Tracking user navigation around the site allows us to analyze trends and demographic information about our entire base of users as a whole. This data is never linked to personal information.

**You Device Addresses:** Every user’s computer has an assigned IP address or device MAC address which is logged upon each visit and action performed on our Website. Your device address is only logged for a temporary period of time and is never provided to third parties unless otherwise stated in this privacy policy. If, at our sole discretion, a visitor is deemed abusive, a device address may be used to block and ban abusive users from viewing the site.

**Web Beacons  **are programing code that may be included on our Website or in email messages. We may use web beacons or similar technologies for the purposes of tracking how users are navigating our Website, count visitors, and monitor effectiveness of email campaigns (how many emails were actually opened, which links were clicked).

**Cookies from Third Party Advertisers:**  We use third party advertising companies and advertising networks on our site. These Third-party companies collect information about your interests when you view or interact with one of their advertisements or the social sharing buttons on our site. Cookies and other technologies are used by these third parties to collect information about how you use the site. This information is gathered by the third parties to predict your interests or preferences in order to display relevant advertisements and promotional materials on our site as well as across the internet aligned with your apparent interests. Information about your device such as IP Address and MAC address may be used by these companies. They may use information about your visits to this website as well as other internet websites in order to serve advertisements that may be relevant to you (such as showing sports advertisements to someone who frequents sports websites). These companies do not collect information on your name, address, email address or telephone number.

  * We do not have control over or access to the technology that may be used by third parties to collect information about your interests. The information collection practices of these third party companies are not covered by this Privacy Policy.
  * For more information about the practice of collecting cookies and to understand your choices to opt out and prevent the use of interest based advertising, please read more here: [http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).
  * Google is one of these third-party vendors who uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s uses a DART cookie which enables them toserve ads based on your visit to this Site and other sites on the internet. To opt out of the use of the DART cookie, visit the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](https://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

## DO WE DISCLOSE INFORMATION TO OUTSIDE PARTIES?

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who process information on our behalf and assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you (including prize fulfillment in a giveaway), so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may release your information only when we believe release is appropriate for compliance with the law, enforcing our site policies, or protecting ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

## THIRD PARTY LINKS:

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer links to other websites including social sharing buttons, links, graphics or banners. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. It is your responsibility to review the privacy policies at those websites to ensure you agree with their privacy policies. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

## CHILDREN’S ONLINE PRIVACY PROTECTION ACT COMPLIANCE:

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not knowingly collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older. We care about protecting children’s privacy. We won’t knowingly allow anyone under 13 to provide personally identifying information. Children who are under 13 should not provide any information about themselves on the internet (including names, email addresses, and phone numbers).

## SECURITY

NatashasKitchen.com maintains a variety of security measures, including using secured networks, to prevent loss, alteration or misuse of information that is collected on this Website. We make no assurances to you or any third party about our ability to prevent any loss, alteration or misuse of information resulting from a third parties loss, misuse, or alteration of information that is collected.

## COMMENTS

Natasha’s Kitchen may use forms such as the comments form. Any information that you disclose in these areas becomes public information. This information may be used, collected or read by other users on our site. Please use caution when disclosing your personal information.

## Visiting our Website from outside the US

For visitors outside of the US, please be aware that your information may stored on servers in the US where our websites servers are located and operated. We take steps to assure proteciton of your privacy but please be aware that your laws may differ than those of the United States. By using our Website, you agree to having your information stored in our US based servers and third parties as stated in this Privacy Policy.

## Online Privacy Policy Only

This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website and not to information collected offline.

## Terms and Conditions

Please also visit our Terms and Conditions section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website at [http://www.natashaskitchen.com/terms-and-conditions](https://natashaskitchen.com/about/terms-and-conditions/)

## Your Consent

By using our site, you consent to our [web site privacy policy](http://www.freeprivacypolicy.com/).

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to change, update or modify our privacy policy at any time without any other notice to you or as required by applicable laws. Any changes will go into effect immediately upon updating on this privacy policy and update the Privacy Policy modification date below. It is your responsibility to review this Privacy Policy periodically to determine if you are still in agreement with all of the terms in this privacy policy.

This policy was last modified on Nov 5, 2018

## Contacting Us

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.

Email: natasha AT natashaskitchen DOT com
